[
    {
        "question": "Lake Constance is shared by which three European countries?",
        "answer": "Austria, Switzerland and Germany -- The international borders inside the lake have never been settled."
    },
    {
        "question": "On the banks of which river is the Taj Mahal?",
        "answer": "Yamuna"
    },
    {
        "question": "Topeka is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "Kansas"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is the capital of the US state of Kansas?",
        "answer": "Topeka"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which island is the Dodo originally from?",
        "answer": "Mauritus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s largest Hydroelectric Power Plant?",
        "answer": "Three Gorges Dam"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is known as the Land of White Elephant?",
        "answer": "Thailand"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the driest continent?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "question": "What currency is used in South Africa?",
        "answer": "Rand"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which African country was formerly known as Abyssinia?",
        "answer": "Ethiopia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mauritius is an island country located in which ocean?",
        "answer": "Indian"
    },
    {
        "question": "What large African island nation is located just west of Mauritius?",
        "answer": "Madagascar"
    },
    {
        "question": "What year did Mauritius gain its independence from Britain?",
        "answer": "1968"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Sierra Leone?",
        "answer": "Freetown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Florence?",
        "answer": "Arno"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Seoul?",
        "answer": "Han"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what Tahitian bay did Captain Cook first land?",
        "answer": "Matavai Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "What capital city is the only one located on the equator?",
        "answer": "Quito, Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mega city`s name translated means `Eastern Capital`?",
        "answer": "Tokyo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the five boroughs of New York City?",
        "answer": "Brooklyn, Queens, The Bronx, Manhattan and Staten Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "Brookline, Cambridge and Quincy are suburbs of what US city?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Neolithic stone circle called Ring of Brodgar located?",
        "answer": "Scotland -- Located on the largest island of the Orkney archipelago off the coast of Scotland, it was likely erected during the Bronze Age around 2,500 B.C."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where on the European continent is located the only population of monkeys living in the wild?",
        "answer": "Gibraltar -- Originally from the Atlas Mountains and the Rif Mountains of Morocco, the Barbary macaque population in Gibraltar has existed for centuries."
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state has the longest coastline?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "Zagreb is the capital of what European country?",
        "answer": "Croatia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What South American country is home to more species of primates, amphibians, and plants than any other in the world?",
        "answer": "Brazil"
    },
    {
        "question": "What color are the stars on China`s flag?",
        "answer": "Yellow"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which European city would you find Orly airport?",
        "answer": "Paris"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is the largest producer of vanilla?",
        "answer": "Madagascar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has Damascus as its capital city?",
        "answer": "Syria"
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S city is nicknamed the `Cradle of Aviation`?",
        "answer": "Dayton, Ohio"
    },
    {
        "question": "The famous commercial port of Sidon is located in which Arab country?",
        "answer": "Lebanon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s most southerly capital city?",
        "answer": "Wellington"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which area of Romania is known as the home of Dracula?",
        "answer": "Transylvania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the third largest Caribbean island?",
        "answer": "Jamaica"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two islands makes up a commonwealth with Antigua?",
        "answer": "Barbuda and Redonda -- The three-island nation is in the Lesser Antilles. Redondo is uninhabited and was formed from a volcano."
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is home to the eighty-eight storey Petronas Twin Towers?",
        "answer": "Kuala Lumpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Yangtze river?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city of Philadelphia is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many time zones does the state of Florida span?",
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did Starbucks open their first location outside of North America?",
        "answer": "Tokyo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which South American country has borders only with Brazil and Argentina?",
        "answer": "Uruguay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bolivia is home to Salar de Uyuni which is the largest what in the world?",
        "answer": "Salt flat"
    },
    {
        "question": "What World Heritage Site`s name translates to `holy wisdom`?",
        "answer": "Hagia Sophia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What word means a British village without a church?",
        "answer": "Hamlet"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the Dominican Republic?",
        "answer": "Santo Domingo"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which US river is the Grand Coulee Dam?",
        "answer": "Columbia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What sea is located directly north of Poland?",
        "answer": "Baltic Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Easter Island, home to mysterious giant stone faces, is owned by what South American country?",
        "answer": "Chile"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city of Roswell, famous for its 1947 UFO incident, is in which state?",
        "answer": "New Mexico"
    }
]